Guide to the Marie Dye collection on the University of Chicago,1919-1972.
Marie Dye collection on the University of Chicago
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Marie Dye collection on the University of Chicago, 1919-1972.
6759
Marie Dye
.7 cubic feet
Correspondence, reports, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, reports and photographs used by Marie Dye to write a book titled, "History of the Department of Home Economics, University of Chicago" (1972).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Marie Dye received three degrees from the University of Chicago: Bachelor of Science (1914), Master of Science (1917), Doctor of Philosophy (1922). She taught at Michigan State University from 1922 to 1956.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, reports and photographs used by Marie Dye to write a book titled, "History of the Department of Home Economics, University of Chicago" (1972).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Dye, Marie.; Blunt, Katharine, 1876-; Porter, Thelma.; Roberts, Lydia J.(Lydia Jane).; University of Chicago.Dept. of Home Economics.; University of Chicago.Dept. of Household Administration.
Subjects:
Home economics--Study and teaching--Illinois--Chicago.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Photograph, Dr. Marie Dye (Box 1)
- Correspondence and publishing materials (Box 1)
- History of the Department of Home Economics, University of Chicago (Home Economics Alumni Association, 1972), 3 folders (Box 1)
- Faculty and alumni
  - Marion Talbot (Box 1)
  - Katharine Blunt (Box 1)
  - Lydia J. Roberts (Box 1)
  - Evelyn G. Halliday (Box 1)
  - Hazel Kyrk (Box 1)
  - Margaret Reid (Box 1)
  - Minna Schmidt (Box 1)
  - Frances Swain (Box 1)
  - Inga Allison (Box 1)
  - Lita Bane (Box 1)
  - Belle Lowe (Box 1)
  - Louise Stanley (Box 1)
  - Bertha Terrill (Box 1)
- Department of Home Economics newsletter, 1935-1965 (Box 1)
- Home Economics Alumni Association, 1944-1967 (Box 1)
- Lists of alumni of the department (Box 1)
- Programs of the Department of Household Administration and Home Economics (Box 2)
- "Application of Heat to Food Materials," laboratory outline (Box 2)
- Course outlines, [contains photographs] (Box 2)
- Katharine Blunt - Chair, 1918-1929
  - The Early Years, 1919-1924 (Box 2)
  - Growth of the department and problems (Box 2)
  - The search for funds (Box 2)
  - Letter to the president by students, 1928 (Box 2)
  - Statement for the president, circa 1925 (Box 2)
- Lydia J. Roberts - Chair, 1930-1945
  - Letter from the alumni to the president, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Reunion program, 1933 (Box 2)
  - Letters and plans for the new organization (Box 2)
  - Institute of Home Economics (Box 2)
  - Plans for granting degrees (Box 2)
  - Evaluations of plans (Box 2)
  - Report of the Administration Policies Committee of the Department of Home Economics, 1945 (Box 2)
  - The search for endowment, 1930-1938 (Box 2)
- Thelma Porter, 1945-1956
  - Correspondence about status (Box 2)
  - Proposed change in the administrative status of the department of Home Economics, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Letters to Dean Harrison, December 1950 (Box 2)
  - Reports, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
  - Last report, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Minutes of faculty meetings, 1944-1956 (Box 2)
- Correspondence about the collection, 1972 (Box 2)
- Photograph album: University of Chicago, 1892-1956 (Box 3)